

Pablo Obando Senior Full Stack Engineer

I'm a passionate full stack developer with over 5 years of experience developing web pages and mobile apps, focused on improving user experiences and ensuring top-notch UI code quality in all project-related processes.

I collaborate with teams to drive software product development, guiding technical decisions from concept to production, ensuring successful project execution.

Work Experience

JUNE 2021 - AUGUST 2023

Senior Full Stack Developer @ Parsley Health

At Parsley Health, a medical practice and healthcare company that focuses on providing personalized and holistic primary care services, I collaborated in impactful projects ensuring timely and budget-compliant deliveries. As part of my responsibilities:

- Participate on the <u>website</u> migration from wordpress to gatsby, including the creation of react components in a storybook for use across multiple websites.
- Participated in the development and ongoing maintenance of core <u>checkout</u> <u>flow</u>, enabling users to effortlessly purchase a membership. Additionally, led implementation of Cypress tests throughout all purchase pathways, guaranteeing thorough testing coverage.
- Implement A/B testing tools and methodologies to drive optimization and glean valuable insights considering user metrics to discern user preferences and behaviors to achieve organizational goals.
- Creation and implementation of endpoints using grpc and graphql, enabling users to have full control over their medical appointments.

typescript react.js node.js graphql next.js tailwind aws

JULY 2019 - JUNE 2021

Full Stack Developer @ Quext

At Quext, a property management platform designed to empower managers and leasing agents by streamlining workflows and automating tasks, all with the goal of elevating property value and enhancing the resident experience. As part of my responsibilities:

- Collaborate in the creation from scratch of an application that empowered property owners to efficiently rent out their apartments.
- Drove improvements to enhance the user experience and functionality of a property rental application.
- The development and maintenance of a content management system (cms) enabling property owners to effortlessly manage their residences.
- Design, and development of an API that facilitated seamless addition,
 editing, and retrieval of apartment information, as well as successfully
 integrating this API into the frontend.

typescript react.js node.js nest.js vue.js tailwind postgresql

JUNE 2018 - JUNE 2019

Full Stack Developer @ <u>Bananacode</u>

At Bananacode, a software company which creates digital solutions around the different needs of the final users. I started as a back end developer and later transitioned into a full stack role, as part of my responsibilities:

- Led a dynamic back end project, collaborating with a team of four developers, to efficiently retrieve information for <u>delfino.cr</u> based on the subscription of the user.
- Designed and developed a flexible subscription system, enhancing user engagement and monetization with tier-based content access.
- Participate in the development and maintenance of content management system (cms) platforms for ecommerce, enabling managers to gain valuable insights into their metrics and effortlessly update their products.
- Designing and maintenance of web components in a storybook for consumption across multiple web applications.

typescript react.js react native node.js graphql mongo.db mysql

SEPTEMBER 2017 - JUNE 2018

Front End Developer @ <u>Nw Ideas</u>

I embarked on my professional journey as a developer in a digital agency in the industry of advertising services. Starting as a junior, I collaborated in challenging projects immersing myself with react and react native, as part of my responsibilities:

- Creation of landing pages from scratch using react.js and html, a variety of css libraries and custom files for responsive design.
- Participate in the development and maintenance of a bank's affiliation score app that enables clients to earn and redeem points with affiliated merchants in compras <u>davivienda</u>. Also the implementation of api's.

javascript react.js react native php css3

Education

MAY 2017 - 2020

Computer Engineering @ Fidélitas University

javascript python html5 oop solid mob programming

Stack

Frameworks & Libraries

mongodb express react.js node.js tailwind cypress

storybook cypress node.js gatsby react native google cloud

apollo graphQl prisma jest firebase styled components

Software & Applications

postgresql discord docker mysql confluence

mongodb jira aws slack figma

Third Party Services

netlify github gitlab vercel

Links

https://obandev.io

https://github.com/obandev
https://twitter.com/obandev io
https://linkedin.com/in/obandev